Toyan George Green

11 Westhaven Drive, Birmingham, B31 1DR, England

toyangreen@gmail.com +44 (0) 7511 934 305 uk.linkedIn.com/in/toyangreen www.toyangreen.com

PROFILE

A highly adaptable software developer with a passion for video games, looking to transition into the games industry. I have 4 years of professional experience in a team orientated, test-driven environment, where I also gained a Scrum Master certification. Currently, I am studying an MSc in Video Game Development at Birmingham City University's Gamer Camp. I am resourceful, self-aware, and have proven myself able to estimate and deliver on self-managed deadlines. I am seeking a position that will utilise my existing skills and encourage further growth to exceed expectations of the role and company goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

September 2015 - September 2019

Rock Solid Knowledge, Bristol

- Shipped 4 greenfield projects
- Cross-platform mobile/web development
- Worked effectively within self-managed teams on large existing codebases
- Contributed to internal projects, tooling and research to fulfil the needs of a growing company
- Frequently assisted with technical and production planning
- Worked effectively from a remote office when necessary

3D Content Developer

June 2015 - July 2015

Ishida Europe Ltd, Birmingham

- Used the Unity game engine to develop "Ishida Expert" training software
- Observed and analysed working machinery to recreate it as accurate simulations

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

MSc Video Game Development

September 2019 – Present

Birmingham City University

- Working as a programmer within multidisciplinary teams
- Gameplay and systems programming on a 2D platformer game for PC using Cocos2d-x
- Programming combat gameplay mechanics and additional tooling for a 3d arena fighting game using Unreal Engine and PlayStation 4 Devkits

MTA: Software Development Fundamentals

March 2020

Microsoft

MTA: Mobility and Device Fundamentals

March 2020

Microsoft

MTA: Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript

March 2020

Microsoft

Certified ScrumMaster®

August 2018

Scrum Alliance

Credential ID: 927495

Birmingham City University

- Dissertation: The use of persuasion in video games (10000 words + supporting Unity game)
- C++ game programming using DirectX, Irrlicht, Irrklang, Assimp
- Maths for A.I. in video games
- IOS and Android mobile app development using web services

SKILLS

Category	Details	Time Used	Last used
Programming Languages	C#	8 years +	2020
	C++	6 years +	2020
	JavaScript	5 years +	2020
Game Engines / Frameworks	Unity	6 years +	2019
	Mono Game / XNA	3 years +	2020
	Unreal Engine	1 year +	2020
	Irrlicht Engine	1 year +	2015
	Direct X	1 year +	2015
	Cocos2d-x	< 1 year	2020
Source Control	Git	6 years +	2020
	Plastic SCM	1 years +	2018
	Perforce	< 1 year	2020
	Subversion	< 1 year	2016
Industry Knowledge	Automated Testing	4 years +	2020
	Agile Project Management	4 years +	2020
	Continuous Integration	4 years +	2019
Systems & Packages	Jira	3 years +	2018
	YouTrack	3 years +	2019
	TeamCity	3 years +	2019
	Hansoft	< 1 year	2019

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

- A designated fire marshal at Rock Solid Knowledge.
- The student representative for The Heights student accommodation, Birmingham.
- A peer mentor within the learning support department of St David's College. I supported the studies of less able students that required extra assistance.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- I love to play and deconstruct games, studying how and why things work. Some of my favourite games include Super Mario World, Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy, Horizon Zero Dawn and God of War.
- I am very passionate about music. I find its ability to conjure powerful feelings and emotions enthralling. I particularly enjoy live music, so I spend a lot of free time at concerts.
- I also really enjoy cooking. It allows me to demonstrate creativity and helps me to socialise with friends and colleagues.

REFERENCES

Available on request